<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOME on Home</title>
    <link>https://terrok9.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HOME on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Edna West: for theme usage search personal-web on Github</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 19:47:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://terrok9.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tidytweets</title>
      <link>https://terrok9.github.io/portfolio/sample-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terrok9.github.io/portfolio/sample-project/</guid>
      <description>This project attemps to enhance the experience you have processing Social Listening Spanish data into working datasets for NLP modeling. In this project, we aim to do all the preprocessing required to establish a good corpus for different types of models, to accomplish that, we redefine tools for lemmatization, emoji and special unicode chars treatment, stopword removal and tokenization for Spanish language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safe Isolation</title>
      <link>https://terrok9.github.io/portfolio/ingreso-solidario/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terrok9.github.io/portfolio/ingreso-solidario/</guid>
      <description>This document explores the heterogeneities in compliance with the isolation measures within the municipalities of Colombia that were treated with Ingreso Solidario program implemented as an unconditional transfer given to poor individuals to face the economic and health emergency caused by Covid-19. Using local mobility data, the announcement of payment of Ingreso Solidario, and effective treatment of the program, a differences-in-differences methodology was proposed under the spectrum of an event study for the first disbursement of the Ingreso Solidario program, this was made in order to find heterogeneities between groups of poorer and richer municipalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcodes</title>
      <link>https://terrok9.github.io/post/shortcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 16:18:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terrok9.github.io/post/shortcodes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction of the shortcodes defined in the personal-web theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel VBA Courses</title>
      <link>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box3/</guid>
      <description>Excel/VBA for Creative Problem Solving, Part 1, 2020. University of Colorado Boulder. Build powerful programming, automation, and customization capabilities available with Visual Basic for Applications (VBA). Certificate link: Excel
Excel/VBA for Creative Problem Solving, Part 2, 2020. University of Colorado Boulder. Learn how to work with arrays and import/export arrays from/to Excel using VBA code. Learn how to work with text strings and write data to .txt files and import information from .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Courses</title>
      <link>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box4/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Deep Learning, 2020. HSE University. Build and test models using Tensorflow including but not limited to Recurrent Neural Network (RNN), Deep Learning, and Convolutional Neural Network (CNN). This modelling were pack with theorical and practical content to fully understand the mathematical and empirical concepts for each type of model. We also had the chance to apply this knowledge on image classification and entity recognition. Certificate link: Machine Learning</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non Programming Courses</title>
      <link>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box5/</guid>
      <description>Firm Level Economics: Consumer and Producer Behavior, 2020. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. Economic concepts of Scarcity, Allocation, and Markets. Followed by a module related to different types of interventions that can occur on a specific market. Finishing with Firm Behavior, Production and Costs. Certificate link: Additional Course
The Data Science of Health Informatics, 2020. Johns Hopkins University. Articulate different forms of clinical and population level data. Describe the data required to answer a healthcare information problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Courses</title>
      <link>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box1/</guid>
      <description>Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python), 2020. University of Michigan. Use variables to store, retrieve and calculate information. Utilize core programming tools such as functions and loops. Certificate link: Python
Python Data Structures, 2020. University of Michigan. Explain the principles of data structures &amp;amp; how they are used. Accomplish multi-step tasks like sorting or looping using tuples. Certificate link: Python
Using Databases with Python, 2020. University of Michigan. Use the Create, Read, Update, and Delete operations to manage databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Courses</title>
      <link>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terrok9.github.io/courses/box2/</guid>
      <description>SQL for Data Science, 2020. UC Davis. Identify a subset of data needed from a column or set of columns and write a SQL query to limit to those results. Create an analysis table from multiple queries using the UNION operator. Use SQL commands to filter, sort, and summarize data. Manipulate strings, dates, &amp;amp; numeric data using functions to integrate data from different sources into fields with the correct format for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
